How do you feel when you hear these words?
Let's go around and introduce ourselves.
Does that make you want a panic, run, or even hide?
Well, you won't any more after you watch this video.
Because I'm going to give you a super simple three-step formula
to introduce yourself professionally with ease and confidence
every single time.
Alright, so this formula has three steps.
First, you're going to say something about the present.
Then you're going to mention something briefly about the past.
And then you're going to end your introduction with something about the future.
So, present, past, future.
And the idea here is to keep your introduction short and sweet.
It should be no longer than about 20 seconds.
Step one, the present.
So, to start your introduction, you're going to say who you are and what you do now.
So, for example, if it's a more formal situation
and you're in a room with people from other companies,
you could say something like,
Hello, everyone.
I'm Jennifer Smith.
I'm a software development manager at ABC Company,
where I'm responsible for the building of new systems
and prevention of issues.
If it's a more informal situation,
stay, you're just starting a new job
and you're introducing yourself to your new co-workers.
You could say something like,
Hi, all.
I'm Joe.
I'm part of the North America Marketing team,
and I'll be looking after generation of new leads.
Now, here, just mention your primary responsibility,
not every single task that you do in your job.
And especially if you're working for an American company,
don't mention any personal details,
like how old you are,
whether you're married or single,
your hobbies just keep it to the professional side.
Quick question before we move on.
Do you have to speak English in your current job right now?
Tell me in the comments, either yes or no.
Alright, moving on to step two of the past.
So now is the time where you're going to want to mention something brief
and relevant about your background.
Something that's going to help people get to know you just a little bit more
and also establishes your credibility.
So think about some things that are relevant to the people you're talking to.
Things like past projects, companies you've worked for other achievements
and just pick one of those things to highlight.
So one example might be,
my background is in computer science.
Before taking on this role,
I work with big data together insights for our clients
and the financial services industry.
Or, I've been with the company for two years now.
Most recently, I was part of the team who worked on campaign ABC,
which brought us client X.
So the key thing here is to keep it brief and irrelevant.
Now is not the time to be telling your whole life story
or giving a summary of your whole CD and resume or your career history.
And step three, the future.
Here you want to end your introduction on a positive note
and show some enthusiasm for the topic at hand.
Communicate some good energy and show the people in the room
that you're happy to be there and you're happy to be involved.
And it can be simple.
For example, you could just say,
it's a pleasure to be here with you all today.
I'm looking very forward to working with you.
Or more informally,
I'm excited to be part of this project.
I think it'll be a great opportunity for all of us.
Alright, now if you put all three of these steps together,
here's an example of how a full introduction might sound.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Maria Shearan.
I'm a marketing manager at ABC Company,
where I'm responsible for lead generation campaigns for North America.
I've been with a company for five years now.
Prior to that, I managed the social media efforts
for company XYZ.
It's a pleasure to be here today
and I'm really looking forward to working with you all in this project.
So just remember, present past future.
Pretty easy, right?
But don't stop there.
Keep practicing your English-speaking skills
that you get more and more comfortable speaking
and English in these kinds of work situations.
And you can do that with this video right here.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you there next.